[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have an
elementary level lesson
for you all about computers.
That's right. So we
are going to take a look
at some of the basic
parts of a computer
and also about bad programs that could
affect your computer and make it not work.
That's right. So before
we get going, we have
a verb for you that
we're going to look at
in vocabulary preview,
very vocabulary preview.
All right. So today
on vocabulary preview,
we have a verb, as you said,
and it's to crash, to crash.
Okay, this has a couple
of different meanings,
but in today's dialogue,
this means for your computer
to shut down or to
freeze or to stop working.
Right. Because maybe
you heard of a car crash,
right, when to crash,
bam, hit each other.
In this case, your computer
is just not working anymore.
It stopped working. It freezes.
That's right. So you can't use it.
So my computer crashed. Is a way to say,
"My computer
stopped working." Okay.
So that's a word that we're going
to listen in our dialogue today.
Why don't we jump right
into it and we'll be back shortly.
[Music]
Hello. Thanks for
calling 123 TechHelp.
I'm Todd. How can I help
you? Hello? Can you help me?
I'm my computer. Oh, man. It's okay, sir.
Calm down. What happened?
I turned on my laptop at a broke.
I mean, the monitor went black.
Okay, sir. It sounds like you might have
a virus. I don't feel sick. I'll be check.
Don't don't fever up fine. No,
your computer might have a virus.
I mean, it has a
bad program on it.
Maybe that's why it
crashed. I recommend that
you run an antivirus
program in order to safely
remove any unwanted
spyware or trojans.
Wait a minute. Crash, spyware,
trojans. What? Where? When?
All right, so lots of great
technology words today.
Let's take a look
at a few of them in
language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, so let's start
off with our first word.
You've probably heard it before,
but let's go over it just in case.
A laptop. A laptop
is a kind of computer.
We have desktop, laptop. Right.
So your lap is the
top part of your legs.
So a laptop computer is a
small portable computer that you
can take with you
anywhere. That's right.
A lot of students have laptops
and businessmen as well.
So you mentioned the
opposite would be a desktop.
Right. So it sits on
top of a desk. Okay.
So both a desktop and a laptop
have monitors, a computer monitor.
So a monitor is like a
TV for your computer.
It's where you can
see what you're doing.
Okay. So it's called a
monitor or a screen, maybe.
You can also use the
word screen, but monitor
is the, the technical
word for the, usually a box,
like a TV that goes with
the desktop computer.
Okay. Very good. So Todd, the computer guy
said, Hey, I think your computer might have
a virus. Oh, that
doesn't sound good.
Yeah, a virus. So I guess
you know what a virus is
when you get sick, right?
You get the flu or the cold.
That's right. You
can say, I have a virus.
But how can a
computer have a virus?
This means it's a program that is
designed to hurt your computer.
All right. So it's like your computer is
sick and it doesn't work. So a virus might
make your computer
crash. Exactly. So in order to
avoid this, what we need
is an antivirus program.
Okay. So virus is a bad
thing. Antivirus is a good thing.
An antivirus program is a program
that protects your computer from viruses.
So you would say antivirus.
You might have heard of a very
famous program called Norton
antivirus or McAfee antivirus.
These are brands.
Okay. Very good.
So those are some of the main technical
terms that we have on language takeaway.
Why don't we listen to our
dialogue quickly once again?
Why don't we listen
to our dialogue quickly
again and we'll be back
with Fluency Builder.
Hello. Thanks for calling 123 Tech Help.
I'm Todd. How can I help you?
Hello. Hello. Can you
help me? I'm my computer.
Oh, man. It's okay, sir.
Calm down. What happened?
I turned on my laptop and broke.
I mean, the monitor went
black. Okay, sir. It sounds like you
might have a virus.
I don't feel sick.
I'll be check. Nope. No fever.
I'm fine. No. Your computer
might have a virus. I mean, it has a bad
program on it. Maybe that's why it crashed.
I recommend that you
run an antivirus program
in order to safely remove
any unwanted spyware
or trojans. Phew. Wait a minute.
Crash spyware trojans. What? Where? When?
All right, we're back.
So now let's start off
with three key phrases
on Fluency Builder.
This first phrase is one
that I know you use a lot.
I use it too. We say,
oh, man. Oh, man.
So now, depending on the tone,
it can mean different things, right?
So in this case,
what does it mean?
So the man who's having problems
with his computer says, my computer.
Oh, man. Right. He
seems a little bit anguished.
Disappointed. Yeah. Oh, man.
So it's an interjection. That's right. So
you can say, oh, man, my computer crashed.
Right. Oh, man.
You're always late.
Now you can also say it for
maybe surprise like, oh, man.
So when you're excited
about something, oh, man,
this computer game is
awesome. Okay. So it's just a
way of expressing maybe
disappointment or in some
cases excitement. That's
right. So think about
the way that you say
it. Oh, man. Oh, man.
Okay. So now the guy taught,
he tells him, hey, sir, it's okay.
Calm down, right? Okay.
So this might be funny
sounding because we say,
calm, so be calm. Calm
down. This is a phrase.
It's almost like you're so
upset and you're standing
up. Calm down. Calm
down. Cool it. Okay.
So you tell someone to
calm down. That's right.
So you might hear a
parent say about their child.
The child won't calm
down. What do I do?
Okay. So it's a phrase.
Let's use it together.
Calm down. Calm down
to calm down. All right.
And now for our third
phrase. I mean, I mean, okay.
So this is also an
interjection and it's
very, very, very common.
Okay. So you'll probably
hear people when
they're talking. They're like,
oh, I went over there. I mean, we
went to this place. It's an interjection.
That's right. And usually we say this
when we want to correct what we just said.
For example, your computer
might have a virus. I mean, it has
a bad program on it. Okay.
So the computer support
man, Todd, he understands
maybe this person doesn't
know what a virus is.
So I mean, he's changing
what he just said. We
could say, oh, Saturday I'm
going to the movie. Sunday,
I'm going to the movies.
Okay, what are you
doing on Sunday? All right.
So you use it to correct
yourself or maybe
further explain something
because maybe you are
talking about a topic and
maybe the person is not
understanding you. So you
want to make it more clear.
That's right. I mean, right.
Like she was very angry at me. I
mean, of course she was because
I did something wrong.
Right. So it's a way to
offer an explanation. All right. So try
and use that one in your speech this week.
It's really, really great common
English phrase. All right.
So why don't we listen
to our dialogue for the
last time and we'll be
back to talk a little bit more.
Hello. Thanks for calling 123 Tech Help.
I'm Todd. How can I help you?
Hello? Can you help
me? I'm my computer.
Oh, man. It's okay, sir.
Calm down. What happened?
I turned on my
laptop at a broke.
I mean, the monitor went
black. Okay, sir. It sounds like you
might have a virus.
I don't feel sick.
I'll be check. Don't, don't
fever up fine. No, your computer
might have a virus. I mean,
it has a bad program on it.
Maybe that's why it crashed.
I recommend that you run an
antivirus program in order to
safely remove any
unwanted spyware or Trojans.
Wait a minute. Crash spyware.
Trojans. Watch. Wear. Win.
All right. So Marco
in today's dialogue, we
heard a couple of strange
words about computer viruses.
One of them, you might be familiar
with from Greek stories and fables.
A Trojan. All right. A
Trojan. So it's a kind
of bad software that
will hurt your computer.
Yeah, it's a it's a type
of virus that comes in.
It's supposed to be a
good program or not harm
your computer, but
it's really just a lie.
It's disguised. It's
something else.
And then it starts to really ruin your
computer. They're very, very dangerous.
Yeah. So why do you think it's called a
Trojan? I don't know. Probably because
of a Troy something, because
it's very difficult like a Trojan.
Well, think about the story of the
Trojan horse, right? You know, that story.
So back in ancient Greece,
there was a war happening.
And Troy wanted to defeat its enemy,
and they didn't know how to do it.
So they thought and thought
and thought and they came up
with an idea. They would
build a horse, and they
would give it as a gift.
But inside the horse
would be warriors,
fighters. Right.
So when the city opened its
doors to this wonderful gift,
they would receive a
horrible gift, an attack.
And so Trojan is
like that. It's like
software that you think is safe, but
then it attacks your computer by surprise.
They're very dangerous. And now
things have come up like Trojans
and worms and a lot of
different names for them.
But it's crazy now, although I hear Mac
users don't have these problems. We do not.
That's if you use a
Macintosh computer, you
probably have very few
problems with viruses and
things like that. Wow.
That's one point in
favor for Mac users.
Absolutely. So let us know,
have you had problems
with a virus on your computer?
Have you ever called
tech support? Our website
is EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you
there. All right. All right, everyone. Bye.